[Music]
hey guys welcome back to another
tutorial my name is mean kakosian today
we're going to focus on the moonwalk the
moonwalk was probably one of the first
steps that I learned as a little boy so
I'm super excited to teach it to you
guys let's not waste any time here we go
[Music]
start this move off uh stand profile so
you can see yourself in the mirror the
first thing you want to do is bring that
right leg up come up on your toes so the
whole idea the illusion is you push with
the right leg to start it off you're
going to slide the left leg back and
you're going to switch weights so the
right leg goes down you push the left
back when you're pushing the left leg
back keep it flat on the ground right
leg is up on toes left leg is flat now
we're going to push we're going to use
all this weight that we have to push
down and Slide the left leg back and
then switch and then on that switch the
left leg comes up the right leg is down
now from here you're going to have to
drag the right leg back okay and when
you drag it stay flat on the floor I've
seen people pick it up do not pick it up
keep it flat on the floor drag it drag
it drag it drag it and then switch okay
from there you do the same thing you're
going to drag the left leg drag switch
okay so let's try one more time right
leg up okay remember up on the toes
you're going to push the leg down you're
going to take the left leg back and one
good now it's really really important
timing wise when the right leg hits flat
on the ground the left leg comes up
together okay so right is down uh right
is up on toes left is flat switch good
and then switch
again switch again okay let's try again
now if you're just starting off and
you're not familiar with this move do it
exactly like I did it with the little
stops so go slide stop get comfortable
with that now you know you have to drag
the right leg and keep the left here
keep dragging it keep it flat on the
ground and switch good from here drag
the
left switch good again doing it slow is
always harder CU you're trying to
balance yourself you're trying to get
the feet right the steps right okay so
one more time right leg is here remember
you could do it with the stops for now
until you get it down and then cut the
stops out and make it smooth seven eight
switch make sure you look good here left
leg up right leg flat down now drag the
right leg back keep it flat and switch
now drag the left
leg switch drag the right leg switch one
more time right leg we'll do a few we'll
just keep going
switch
switch switch okay let's do the same
thing coming back left leg is up right
leg is here same exact thing you're
going to push down with the
left
one
3 4 good now let's do the same thing
without the stops in the middle but
we'll still do it slow here we go six
7 8 go one 2 3 4
78 and one 2 3 4 good one more time 6 7
8 1 2 3 4 good and also um make sure
there's good distance between your legs
when you slide some people do it super
close which is fine but the bigger it is
the better it's going to look so imagine
if you look like you're just gliding
down the floor boom boom boom yeah so
I'm keeping a lot of distance between my
legs so you really see the slide okay
let's do it one more time right leg up
let's drag the left switch good you see
the distance between my legs this allows
me to push that right leg all the way so
you can see that Glide and then switch
now the left leg
switch now the right leg switch good now
once you get that down what makes it
even look cooler is if you could use
your neck and you could use your body so
imagine you're doing all of that and
then using your neck using your body
yeah and gliding with it okay so one
more time slow idea is here right leg
toes left
leg
switch
switch switch good all right guys so I
know I'm going to get the question um
regarding the floor does the floor have
to be smooth it all depends on the how
how good you could do it so if you
practice it enough you could do it on
concrete you could do it on wood floor
you could do it anywhere you like as
long as you know what you're doing okay
you'll adjust accordingly even with your
shoes you might be like my shoes don't
work because it doesn't slide it doesn't
matter if you could do the move you'll
figure out how to adjust it so first yes
find somewhere slippery work on it there
um do it with your socks if you want to
that always helps that's how I learned I
did it with my socks in the very
beginning before I even put the shoes on
um whatever gets you to Glide easier
when you're learning do it from there
then you can once you have it down you
could do it on any floor you want okay
so let's try it one more time here we go
five six seven eight we're going one two
three four good one more time going back
7 8 1 2 3 4 all right guys here we go
what music five 6 5 6 7 go one 2 3 4
five six good going back that way here
we go five six 7 8 1 2 3 4 5 6
[Music]
ah ah